I want to be a fairy tale author.
Yes.
I am already 31 and can't make enough money as a fairy tale author. So I got a job as a technical writer.
I feel alienated and unhappy because I am writing things like articles and editorials, which I am not interested in.
But I can't quit my job, so I feel like I am being dragged along.
I should give up material goods to pursue my dreams, but I can't. So I would like to ask you what I should do.
Oh really? I would like to be a respectable monk but, at the same time, have a wife at home, drive a nice car, eat whatever I want, and have everyone bow to me.
Does this make any sense to you? You are not making much sense either.
You just want to write while everything else is taken care of for you.
That's like me saying that I want to sit around in my temple but have large crowds of people come to hear me speak.
You shouldn't have such empty dreams. You are too young to do that.
First, if you are older than 20 years, you should be responsible for your livelihood.
You need to take care of your own necessities.
Beyond what age? Beyond 20.
If you can't move out of your parents' house, this is what you should do.
If you calculate your room and board to be about $500, you should do $500 worth of chores at your parents' house.
So, instead of eating breakfast your mom makes, you can cook breakfast for your parents.
You clean your own room and do the laundry for your family. You need to be responsible for your livelihood, regardless of your family's financial situation.
Then, your mind will be healthier. Being dependent on others will have the opposite effect.
So, I tell parents to kick their children out when they turn 20.
If they don't leave, draw up a contract and collect rent.
If they can't pay the rent, start charging interest.
This is how they become independent. This is how they foster a healthy mind.
So it's quite fortunate that you have a job to support yourself.
If you fail to keep this job, you can instead work as a housekeeper or a janitor to support yourself.
Then you can write what you want by forgoing leisure and social time and sleeping a little less.
By not worrying about making a living through writing, you will be able to write to the best of your ability.
If people like your writing, that's great. If they don't, your livelihood will not be affected.
If enough people like your writing so you can make a living from it, you can quit your job and write professionally.
But what you are telling me right now doesn't make any sense.
I need my imagination to write fairy tales. But, after a long day of dry, technical writing, I don't even want to turn on my computer.
You can't force writing like that.
It doesn't work that way. It seems that writing is not right for you.
You have to want to write so badly that you'd be willing to pay money to do it. If you truly want to write, inspiration can come to you even in the restroom.
If you have to work so hard to write your stories, they won't be fun for anybody including yourself. You shouldn't write like that. But, since I started working, I haven't been able to write one single story.
I started writing before I got my current job, and I loved it and was very confident.
Then don't write. It's not a big deal.
But I have a desire to write.
If you have a desire, it means you really want to write. You are contradicting yourself.
If you really have the desire to write, you should simply write, even in the restroom.
Did the famous painters of the past paint to make money or simply because they wanted to?
They painted simply because they wanted to. Now hundred years later, some of those paintings are priceless.
You say you need to use your imagination. It sounds like an obligation.
How can you expect to touch people when you write out of obligation?
Write only those things that naturally pour out.
In the past, when there were fewer writers contrived writings was accepted, but no one reads such writings any more.
Who would want to read stories that give them headaches?
Stop being so foolish. Don't write if you are too busy with your work to write.
When you can't stop yourself from writing despite being so busy, the writing will be meaningful.
How about I change to a more physical job?
That is up to you.
Okay. Thank you.